[
    {
        "question": "List all hotels which are in London. Order the result in descending order by hotel name.",
        "answer": "SELECT * FROM hotel WHERE city ='London' ORDER BY hotelname DESC;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all hotels whose name’s third alphabet has a ‘t’.",
        "answer": "SELECT * FROM hotel WHERE hotelname LIKE '__t%';"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all bookings whose dateto column is NULL.",
        "answer": "SELECT * FROM booking WHERE dateto IS NULL;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List the guest name and guest address of those guests who are from Glasgow and their first name is Tony or last name is Farrel.",
        "answer": "SELECT guestname, guestaddress FROM guest WHERE guestaddress LIKE '%Glasgow%' AND (guestname LIKE 'Tony%' OR guestname LIKE '% Farrel');"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all the room nos. which were booked in the period 2005-2010. Also display the room’s hotel no.",
        "answer": "SELECT roomno, hotelno FROM booking WHERE YEAR(datefrom) BETWEEN 2005 AND 2010;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all the rooms of hotel no. 1001 which are of single type and the price is between 20 to 40.",
        "answer": "SELECT * FROM room WHERE hotelno = '1001' AND [type] = 'single' AND price BETWEEN 20 AND 40;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List the room no. along with its hotel no. whose price is maximum.",
        "answer": "SELECT roomno + '-' + hotelno AS roomHotelNo FROM room WHERE price = (SELECT MAX(price) FROM room); SELECT CONCAT(roomno , '-', hotelno) AS roomHotelNo FROM room WHERE price = (SELECT MAX(price) FROM room);"
    },
    {
        "question": "Show the data of hotel table as : The hotel whose id is (id) is in (city) and its name is (name). Example: The hotel whose is id isdc01 is in Berlin and its name is Latham.",
        "answer": "SELECT 'The hotel whose is id ' + hotelno + ' is in ' + city + ' and its name is ' + [hotelname] FROM hotel; SELECT CONCAT('The hotel whose is id ', hotelno, ' is in ', city, ' and its name is ', [hotelname]) FROM hotel;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all the hotels which have double as well as family type rooms.",
        "answer": "SELECT DISTINCT h.* FROM hotel AS h JOIN room AS r1 ON r1.hotelno = h.hotelno JOIN room AS r2 ON r1.hotelno = h.hotelno WHERE r1.type = 'double' AND r2.type ='family';"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all the hotels which have single as well as double type rooms but no family type room.",
        "answer": "SELECT DISTINCT h.* FROM hotel AS h JOIN room AS r1 ON r1.hotelno = h.hotelno AND r1.type = 'single' JOIN room AS r2 ON r1.hotelno = h.hotelno AND r2.type = 'double' LEFT JOIN room AS r3 ON r3.hotelno = h.hotelno AND r3.type = 'family' WHERE r3.roomno IS NULL;"
    },
    {
        "question": "List all the rooms which have been booked by either guest no. 10003 or by guest no. 1007 but not by guest no 1001.",
        "answer": "SELECT * FROM booking WHERE (guestno = 10003 OR guestno = 1007) AND guestno != 1001;"
    }
]
